<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<link rel="hub" href="https://miklb.superfeedr.com"/>

  <title type="text" xml:lang="en"></title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-15T22:50:57Z</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <rights type="text">Copyright © 2016 . All rights reserved.</rights>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rough Take on Jekyll</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/rough-take-on-jekyll/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/rough-take-on-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>In a longer discussion about the recent pitch by Medium to content creators to move to their platform and options for new companies to build a site on, this nugget on whether Jekyll is an option:</p>

<blockquote>
Only usable by developers. About as accessible as improv Klingon slam poetry to anybody else.

- <cite><a href="https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/notes/choosing-a-host">Baldur Bjarnason</a> </cite>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Solving the Mysterious Relaunching iTunes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/solving-the-mysterious-relaunching-itunes/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-05T14:57:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-05T14:57:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/solving-the-mysterious-relaunching-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I had been plagued by an issue on my Macbook Air the last couple of months where iTunes would relaunch mysteriously. Not random relaunch mysteriously, more like, as soon as I quit, it would relaunch. I tried force quit and restarts. I trashed cache files and rebuilt the library to no avail. I filed bug reports and feedback to iTunes. Finally I reached out to @AppleSupport on Twitter. Right after (mind you, I DM’ed the account as they asked and so far no further reply) my internet friend <a href="https://twitter.com/shep">@shep</a> linked to a blog post of his from 4 years ago with his own <a href="https://iamshep.net/2012/08/the-never-ending-saga-of-itunes-launching-itself/">saga of iTunes relaunching</a>. I read through, and while I didn’t have headphones plugged in, I have dozed off a few times with my headphones in, and maybe, as he read about the microswitch in the jack, maybe, just maybe the headphones pulled out slightly &amp; not depressing said microswitch. So I forcefully inserted some headphones and quickly pulled the plug out of the jack. I quit iTunes and <em>so far</em>, iTunes hasn’t relaunched.</p>

<p>Did I mention @AppleSupport hasn’t followed up yet?</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Building a Twitterbot</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/building-a-twitterbot/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/building-a-twitterbot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I had an interest to learn the programming language python for quite some time. I’ve played around with it a little using <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/pythonista/id528579881?at=10lKmy">Pythonista</a> in iOS to <a href="https://miklb.com/use-pythonista-to-get-weather-of-current-location-into-drafts-app">build a fishing log</a>, but otherwise have only done some cursory reading. Since I do best learning by doing, I needed an idea to <strong>use</strong> python. I’ve seen some interesting Twitterbots built with it, <a href="https://twitter.com/pomological">@pomological</a> being my recent favorite, but wasn’t sure what to build. Ultimately, the idea came to me to build a bot that retrieves an image from Flickr and builds a color scheme from that and post the scheme and original image. I’ve done some basic research and found some libraries to connect (you didn’t think I was going to write the whole thing from scratch?).</p>

<p>But I don’t just want a any random image, so once I get the bot <em>working</em>, I want to be able to try and pull outdoor/landscape images. In a perfect world, I would post 3 images a day—morning, noon, and night. The morning image would be a sunrise, noon/daytime image a normal image and, you guessed it, the night/evening image would be a sunset.</p>

<p>I figured I needed a name for the Twitterbot, not only to make sure something would be available, but since I would need API keys, that has been my first tangible step to create the bot. Thus, @Flickolorbot has been officially conceived.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more adventures.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Few Thoughts About WordPress REST API and Core</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/a-few-thoughts-about-wordpress-rest-api-and-core/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-02-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/a-few-thoughts-about-wordpress-rest-api-and-core</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>There has been much written about the ~drama~ discussions surrounding the <a href="http://v2.wp-api.org">WordPress REST API</a> and inclusion in core. Or exclusion, depending on who’s take you are reading. <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup> Suffice to say, the gist I’ve gathered is that there are two competing perspectives, one side wants to incrementally add the API, the other wants a fully fleshed out, complete API before inclusion in core.</p>

<p>I guess my 2¢ on the matter is this—the core tenet of the <a href="http://wordpressfoundation.org">WordPress Foundation</a> is “to democratize publishing through Open Source, GPL software.” From what I’ve gathered reading on the subject, the REST API team have the publishing portion of the API covered and ready for inclusion in core. The parts that would come (much) later would be things like the customizer, file editing, more site <strong>management</strong> tools, less about actually publishing.</p>

<p>If democratized publishing is still the guiding principle for WordPress the project, then I don’t see how there is any debate. Opening up the methods to publish beyond what has been the only means available for basically the entire life of the project seems like a no brainer to this guy who’s been around it for 11 years this year. No one will truly know how much is opened up until it is in the hands of creative developers and then in the hands of content creators.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m specifically not linking to any of the <em>hot takes</em> on the subject. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Text Expander snippet for Jekyll With Slug for Permalink</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/text-expander-snippet-for-jekyll-with-slug-for-permalink/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-02-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/text-expander-snippet-for-jekyll-with-slug-for-permalink</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>There are plenty of TextExpander snippets floating around for creating Jekyll Front Matter, however, I wanted to take it a step further, and auto-create a slugified permalink with no additional work. The other part of the equation was that I wanted it to be able to use it on TE touch, which meant it had to be done in javascript. After a little Googling, some trial and error, I came up with one that takes a text input for the post title, generates a slug from that, and includes the current date. I understand that the date in the file can be used, however I may not always publish when the file was initially created. Not to mention, when I imported all of my posts from Habari, I needed to be able to use the original post date, not the date the file was created, so I continue to use that. You can certainly modify the snippet for your needs.</p>

<p>Also note, I have a blank variable for <em>summary</em>. Since I’m using webmentions, I use the summary as the text for a tweet, which would be different than an excerpt. Some of this may change when I redo the site redesign, but for now, it’s how I roll.</p>

<p>I would love feedback on how to make the snippet better as it’s my first javascript snippet. Just leave a comment on the gist.</p>

<noscript><pre>var title = &#39;%filltext:name=Title%&#39;;
slug = title.replace(/[^\w\s]/gi, &#39;&#39;);
var newslug = title.split(&quot; &quot;).join(&quot;-&quot;);

var dt = new Date();

TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;---\n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;layout: post \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;title: &quot; + &#39;&quot;&#39; +title + &#39;&quot;&#39;+ &quot;\n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;tags: \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;published: true \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;permalink: &quot;) +TextExpander.appendOutput(newslug.toLowerCase()); + TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot; \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;date: &quot;) + TextExpander.appendOutput(dt.getFullYear() + &quot;-&quot; +(dt.getMonth() +1) + &quot;-&quot; + dt.getDate()) + TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;\n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;summary: \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;--- \n&quot;);

// %filltop%</pre></noscript>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/miklb/53a93032fb8cc669b1fa.js"> </script>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First Listen: Luther Dickinson</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/first-listen-luther-dickinson/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-02-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/first-listen-luther-dickinson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p><cite>Garden &amp; Gun</cite> have a <a href="http://gardenandgun.com/blog/first-listen-luther-dickinson-blues-ballads">first listen of Luther Dickinson’s</a> solo album <cite>Blues &amp; Ballads.</cite> If you’re not familiar with Dickinson, he was a founding member of the band North Missippi All-Stars, a raucous blues band hailing from their name sake Mississippi. Founded with his brother, they played a modern version of the blues soaked southern rock, with an emphasis on the former. I had the pleasure of seeing them both in a smaller outdoor club setting as well as a larger festival type setting, both times blowing the doors off the crowd. Not sure his vocals will ever be considered above average, but the accompanying vocals from the likes of Mavis Staples balances it out. The lyrics and guitars more than make up for his singing, and its obvious the apple didn’t fall from the tree, as you can tell he knows his way around the studio.</p>

<p>As first listens go, I’m enjoying it and will certainly be added to the rotation the next week.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Focused Blogs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/focused-blogs/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-01-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/focused-blogs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>In my ever revolving attempt to reboot my blog, one thing that has always slowed me down was my concern with being too esoteric in my topics. I want to talk about food, technology and everything in between.</p>

<p>However, if I want to build any readership (isn’t that a part of blogging, sharing your thoughts with others?) I can’t be mixing in posts about forays into Python with posts about cooking vegetables sous-vide. Sure, there might be a readership that is interested in both topics as I am, but not enough to say “screw it.” So as I continue to work towards a true <a href="https://indiewebcamp.com">indieweb</a>, I’m pivoting a bit in my approach and will use this as domain, now 11 years old, as my base identifier and central clearing house. I’ve acquired several domains, 2 of which will be good to split the topics. Those too will be static Jekyll built sites, with links from this site to new posts.</p>

<p>Certainly this is more me thinking out loud and putting it out there, as I intend for this domain to be, but my goal is to continue to do such here, rather than bottle  up my thoughts in my head.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Finally Webmentions with Jekyll</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/finally-webmentons-with-jekyll-part-duex/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-01-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/finally-webmentions-with-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>If you can’t tell by previous posts, I’ve been working on getting
<a href="https://indiewebcamp.com/Webmention">Webmentions</a> to work with my new Jekyll site. I <em>think</em> I’ve finally nailed. If you take a look at my initial post <a href="http://miklb.com/making-the-move-to-jekyll">on moving to Jekyll</a>, there’s a link for a tutorial on using Travis CI to build a branch and move the flat files into the mater branch to be served on GitHub. With the help of a Aaron Gustafson’s <a href="https://github.com/aarongustafson/jekyll-webmention_io">Webmention.io plugin</a> I finally have it working. The trick was that the rakefile was firing in the build process too fast, so webmention.io couldn’t find the post on my domain, thus not sending the mention. My probably not so elegant solution was to put a <code class="highlighter-rouge">sleep 2m</code> in my shell script to slow things down and let GitHub catchup before firing the rakefile and sending the mentions. This post will be my final test. If all goes well, I will try and write up a more detailed explanation of what I’ve done since there’s still a lot missing for doing this with a Jekyll site.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Breaking Out of the Silo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/breaking-out-of-the-silo/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-01-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/breaking-out-of-the-silo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>In my never ending quest to make this site all things “miklb”, one of the goals of the IndieWeb is to <a href="http://indiewebcamp.com/POSSE">POSSE</a>, that is, Publish on your own site, syndicate elsewhere. Breaking the habit of using Twitter without posting first on my site is going to be a hard one, but it’s a goal. While debates rage about extending character counts to 10,000 words, if we only were to use our blog for long form thoughts and link back to Twitter, this wouldn’t be an issue. Consider this an exercise in</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Testing Sending Webmentions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/testing-sending-webmentions/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-01-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/testing-sending-webmentions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>This is either going to go well, or well, not so well. But we are getting there. Slowly.  Last one for the night. Take 2. Day 2.<a href="https://kartikprabhu.com/notes/test-note-totally-te" class="u-in-reply-to">Thanks for the help Kartik</a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>
