<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<link rel="hub" href="https://miklb.superfeedr.com"/>

  <title type="text" xml:lang="en"></title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-24T07:04:04Z</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <rights type="text">Copyright © 2016 Michael Bishop. All rights reserved.</rights>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Customizing Atom Editor</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/customizing-atom-editor/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-22T03:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-22T03:15:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/customizing-atom-editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I doubt anyone who writes code for a living or tinkers for that matter hasn’t spent more hours than they’d care to admit tweaking their editor of choice. Suffice to say, I’m in that boat all to well.</p>

<p>My current editor of choice is <a href="http://atom.io">Atom</a>. It’s open source and more than fits the customization itch.</p>

<p>Aside from deciding on which packages to use (I’ve
<a href="https://atom.io/users/miklb/stars">starred the ones I use</a>) the other element I’ve gone back and forth with is theme &amp; syntax UI. I’ve long been a fan of both Solarized Light and Dark, but have finally settled on Atom Dark and <a href="https://atom.io/themes/oceanic-next">Oceanic Next</a>. I can also recommend <a href="https://olivermak.es">Oliver Pattison’s</a> <a href="https://atom.io/users/opattison">Newbound syntax themes</a> My dream font is Operator Mono, but until I can justify the purchase of that, I’m using <a href="http://input.fontbureau.com/info/">Input</a>.</p>

<p>One tweak I just discovered is for adjusting the font size in the panel, or the sidebar. I’d been able to easily make the font larger for code/markdown, but sometimes had to break the readers out to discern what file was what in a nested folder. To the rescue I found <code class="highlighter-rouge">atom-panel.tool-panel</code> for just that. I’m currently using <code class="highlighter-rouge">1.4em</code>. Mind you this is on my old 11 inch Air. I’ve not had as much an issue on the iMac.</p>

<p>Another tweak I’ve added to my custom <code class="highlighter-rouge">styles.less</code> file is to italicize attributes. I’m also a fan of italicized comment blocks, which is included in the snippet.</p>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="na">atom-text-editor</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="n">shadow</span><span class="err">{</span>
     <span class="nc">.entity.other.attribute-name</span> <span class="err">{</span>
         <span class="nl">font-style</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nb">italic</span><span class="err">;</span>
     <span class="err">}</span>

     <span class="nc">.comment</span> <span class="err">{</span>
       <span class="nl">font-style</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nb">italic</span><span class="err">;</span>
     <span class="err">}</span>
 <span class="err">}</span>
</code></pre>
</div>
<p>I’m sure as I expand my development world, (I have a goal to learn python by <a href="https://miklb.com/building-a-twitterbot">Building a Twitterbot</a> ) I’ll continue to tweak Atom, but for now, I’m as close to happy with an editor as I have ever been. Feel free to share with me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/miklb">@miklb</a> your tips and trick.
<a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Interest in Tampa Homebrew Website Club?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/interest-in-tampa-homebrew-website-club/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-19T14:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-19T14:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/interest-tampa-homebrew-website-club</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Gauging interest in Tampa to see if anyone would be up for joining a
<a href="https://indiewebcamp.com/events/2016-04-06-homebrew-website-club">Homebrew Website Club</a>. A lot of tech folks have vey neglected personal sites and this would give folks a chance to get together and talk tech and work on their personal site and pet proejcts. Platform agnostic (read, not another WordPress meetup) so open to anyone. If interested ping me on <a href="https://twitter.com/miklb">Twitter @miklb</a> for now and I’ll sort out finding a location and setting up a time. Only looking for a couple of people to get off the ground.</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Headings - What Was Old is New Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/headings-what-was-old-is-new-again/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-18T13:10:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-18T13:10:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/headings-what-was-old-is-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Seems HTML WG has reversed course on a previous recommendation that allowed <code class="highlighter-rouge">sections</code> to have their own <code class="highlighter-rouge">H1</code> tag, now recommending the previous norm of cascading H tags.</p>

<blockquote>
Given that this bug has been around, and not fixed in browsers, for many  
years, we are proposing to remove the suggestion, and return to the model  
where elements `h1..h6` have a defined level of their own.
<cite><a href="https://lists.w3.org/Archives/Public/public-html/2016Apr/0032.html">HTML WG</a></cite>


<a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a>
</blockquote>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dogfooding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/dogfooding/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-17T17:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-17T17:27:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/dogfooding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Last night I switched over the <em>theme</em> for this site to a project I’ve been working on the last moth or so, <a href="https://github.com/miklb/jekyll-indieweb">Jekyll-IndieWeb</a>. While I have different design ideas, until I find other users interested in using it, I knew I needed to work out any kinks. I also wanted to have better microformat support until the design changes. Thus
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eating_your_own_dog_food">dogfooding</a>.</p>

<p>I will write more about the project once I have more documentation (and work out any more said kinks), but the gist is I wanted to provide someone new to Jekyll with a desire to be part of the
<a href="https://indiewebcamp.com/">IndieWeb</a> a solid starting point. I rely heavily on the <code class="highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> file for options a user can set - profile pic, social media links, choice to include display of webmentions - to quickly get a personal site up and running. The biggest hurdle for me was providing a minimal design that was unopinionated yet still aesthetically appealing. Anyone familiar with HTML &amp; CSS can easily build upon or modify it, but if not, it shouldn’t look <em>ugly</em>.</p>

<p>This has been the first solo project I’ve embarked on that was meant for public consumption from the start, which in itself has been a learning process. Now I just hope others can find it useful in some way. If the project interests you I encourage you to try it out, open any issues in the repo, or reach out on #indiewebcamp IRC, I tend to hang around there most days.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rough Take on Jekyll</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/rough-take-on-jekyll/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/rough-take-on-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>In a longer discussion about the recent pitch by Medium to content creators to move to their platform and options for new companies to build a site on, this nugget on whether Jekyll is an option:</p>

<blockquote>
Only usable by developers. About as accessible as improv Klingon slam poetry to anybody else.

- <cite><a href="https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/notes/choosing-a-host">Baldur Bjarnason</a> </cite>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Solving the Mysterious Relaunching iTunes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/solving-the-mysterious-relaunching-itunes/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-05T14:57:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-05T14:57:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/solving-the-mysterious-relaunching-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I had been plagued by an issue on my Macbook Air the last couple of months where iTunes would relaunch mysteriously. Not random relaunch mysteriously, more like, as soon as I quit, it would relaunch. I tried force quit and restarts. I trashed cache files and rebuilt the library to no avail. I filed bug reports and feedback to iTunes. Finally I reached out to @AppleSupport on Twitter. Right after (mind you, I DM’ed the account as they asked and so far no further reply) my internet friend <a href="https://twitter.com/shep">@shep</a> linked to a blog post of his from 4 years ago with his own <a href="https://iamshep.net/2012/08/the-never-ending-saga-of-itunes-launching-itself/">saga of iTunes relaunching</a>. I read through, and while I didn’t have headphones plugged in, I have dozed off a few times with my headphones in, and maybe, as he read about the microswitch in the jack, maybe, just maybe the headphones pulled out slightly &amp; not depressing said microswitch. So I forcefully inserted some headphones and quickly pulled the plug out of the jack. I quit iTunes and <em>so far</em>, iTunes hasn’t relaunched.</p>

<p>Did I mention @AppleSupport hasn’t followed up yet?</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Building a Twitterbot</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/building-a-twitterbot/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/building-a-twitterbot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I had an interest to learn the programming language python for quite some time. I’ve played around with it a little using <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/pythonista/id528579881?at=10lKmy">Pythonista</a> in iOS to <a href="https://miklb.com/use-pythonista-to-get-weather-of-current-location-into-drafts-app">build a fishing log</a>, but otherwise have only done some cursory reading. Since I do best learning by doing, I needed an idea to <strong>use</strong> python. I’ve seen some interesting Twitterbots built with it, <a href="https://twitter.com/pomological">@pomological</a> being my recent favorite, but wasn’t sure what to build. Ultimately, the idea came to me to build a bot that retrieves an image from Flickr and builds a color scheme from that and post the scheme and original image. I’ve done some basic research and found some libraries to connect (you didn’t think I was going to write the whole thing from scratch?).</p>

<p>But I don’t just want a any random image, so once I get the bot <em>working</em>, I want to be able to try and pull outdoor/landscape images. In a perfect world, I would post 3 images a day—morning, noon, and night. The morning image would be a sunrise, noon/daytime image a normal image and, you guessed it, the night/evening image would be a sunset.</p>

<p>I figured I needed a name for the Twitterbot, not only to make sure something would be available, but since I would need API keys, that has been my first tangible step to create the bot. Thus, @Flickolorbot has been officially conceived.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more adventures.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Few Thoughts About WordPress REST API and Core</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/a-few-thoughts-about-wordpress-rest-api-and-core/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-02-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/a-few-thoughts-about-wordpress-rest-api-and-core</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>There has been much written about the ~drama~ discussions surrounding the <a href="http://v2.wp-api.org">WordPress REST API</a> and inclusion in core. Or exclusion, depending on who’s take you are reading. <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup> Suffice to say, the gist I’ve gathered is that there are two competing perspectives, one side wants to incrementally add the API, the other wants a fully fleshed out, complete API before inclusion in core.</p>

<p>I guess my 2¢ on the matter is this—the core tenet of the <a href="http://wordpressfoundation.org">WordPress Foundation</a> is “to democratize publishing through Open Source, GPL software.” From what I’ve gathered reading on the subject, the REST API team have the publishing portion of the API covered and ready for inclusion in core. The parts that would come (much) later would be things like the customizer, file editing, more site <strong>management</strong> tools, less about actually publishing.</p>

<p>If democratized publishing is still the guiding principle for WordPress the project, then I don’t see how there is any debate. Opening up the methods to publish beyond what has been the only means available for basically the entire life of the project seems like a no brainer to this guy who’s been around it for 11 years this year. No one will truly know how much is opened up until it is in the hands of creative developers and then in the hands of content creators.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m specifically not linking to any of the <em>hot takes</em> on the subject. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Text Expander snippet for Jekyll With Slug for Permalink</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/text-expander-snippet-for-jekyll-with-slug-for-permalink/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-02-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/text-expander-snippet-for-jekyll-with-slug-for-permalink</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>There are plenty of TextExpander snippets floating around for creating Jekyll Front Matter, however, I wanted to take it a step further, and auto-create a slugified permalink with no additional work. The other part of the equation was that I wanted it to be able to use it on TE touch, which meant it had to be done in javascript. After a little Googling, some trial and error, I came up with one that takes a text input for the post title, generates a slug from that, and includes the current date. I understand that the date in the file can be used, however I may not always publish when the file was initially created. Not to mention, when I imported all of my posts from Habari, I needed to be able to use the original post date, not the date the file was created, so I continue to use that. You can certainly modify the snippet for your needs.</p>

<p>Also note, I have a blank variable for <em>summary</em>. Since I’m using webmentions, I use the summary as the text for a tweet, which would be different than an excerpt. Some of this may change when I redo the site redesign, but for now, it’s how I roll.</p>

<p>I would love feedback on how to make the snippet better as it’s my first javascript snippet. Just leave a comment on the gist.</p>

<noscript><pre>var title = &#39;%filltext:name=Title%&#39;;
slug = title.replace(/[^\w\s]/gi, &#39;&#39;);
var newslug = title.split(&quot; &quot;).join(&quot;-&quot;);

var dt = new Date();

TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;---\n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;layout: post \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;title: &quot; + &#39;&quot;&#39; +title + &#39;&quot;&#39;+ &quot;\n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;tags: \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;published: true \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;permalink: &quot;) +TextExpander.appendOutput(newslug.toLowerCase()); + TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot; \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;date: &quot;) + TextExpander.appendOutput(dt.getFullYear() + &quot;-&quot; +(dt.getMonth() +1) + &quot;-&quot; + dt.getDate()) + TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;\n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;summary: \n&quot;);
TextExpander.appendOutput(&quot;--- \n&quot;);

// %filltop%</pre></noscript>
<script src="https://gist.github.com/miklb/53a93032fb8cc669b1fa.js"> </script>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First Listen: Luther Dickinson</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/first-listen-luther-dickinson/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-02-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/first-listen-luther-dickinson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p><cite>Garden &amp; Gun</cite> have a <a href="http://gardenandgun.com/blog/first-listen-luther-dickinson-blues-ballads">first listen of Luther Dickinson’s</a> solo album <cite>Blues &amp; Ballads.</cite> If you’re not familiar with Dickinson, he was a founding member of the band North Missippi All-Stars, a raucous blues band hailing from their name sake Mississippi. Founded with his brother, they played a modern version of the blues soaked southern rock, with an emphasis on the former. I had the pleasure of seeing them both in a smaller outdoor club setting as well as a larger festival type setting, both times blowing the doors off the crowd. Not sure his vocals will ever be considered above average, but the accompanying vocals from the likes of Mavis Staples balances it out. The lyrics and guitars more than make up for his singing, and its obvious the apple didn’t fall from the tree, as you can tell he knows his way around the studio.</p>

<p>As first listens go, I’m enjoying it and will certainly be added to the rotation the next week.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>
