<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<link rel="hub" href="https://miklb.superfeedr.com"/>

  <title type="text" xml:lang="en"></title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-28T18:53:16Z</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <rights type="text">Copyright © 2016 Michael Bishop. All rights reserved.</rights>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Testing MicroPub</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/title/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-28T15:24:16Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-28T15:24:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>/testing-micro-pub</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>What is going to happen?</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Productivity Status Early 2016</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/productivity-status-early-2016/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-25T19:45:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-25T19:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/productivity-status-early-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I broke one of my new rules today by tweeting out more than politics snark or sports and briefly outlined the direction I’m moving with my <em>productivity</em> this year. I’ve been toiling the past year or so trying to shoehorn my brain into Omnifocus to no avail, so at the beginning of the year I started exploring other methods. About 2 weeks ago, my brain just started to work in regard to using <a href="https://www.taskpaper.com">TaskPaper</a>. If you aren’t familiar with TaskPaper, it is a plain text method of tracking todos that has tools built around it to filter by tags and projects. I’ve owned the app for awhile, but not until 3.0 was in beta did things begin to click within the app in regard to organizing projects. I always wanted (wrongly) to keep separate files for each project. Maybe that is one thing I learned using Omnifocus was structuring projects. Now everything personal is one single text file. I do have a separate one for the free lance work I’m doing because that’s a different mode. I don’t want to be distracted by anything when I’m trying to mow through items for work.</p>

<p>The other element of my productivity was how to keep and better use Reminders.app and Siri. I knew TaskPaper had Applescript support, so that was the first place I looked. Sure enough, I found a script that would import from Reminders to TaskPaper. Unfortunately, TP3 changed it’s scripting method to new JXA, so the old Applescripts were not compatible. Luckily, someone did the work before I fried synapses trying to learn more advanced methods of JXA. A thread in the support forums,
<a href="http://support.hogbaysoftware.com/t/appending-items-to-a-taskpaper-file-using-siri/1456/9">Using Siri</a> covered exactly what I wanted.</p>

<p>From there, I devised the idea of having an “Inbox” for Siri and a corresponding list for TP. I also have a Grocery List and my main reminders is for timed items. I prefer Apple’s reminders because it’s nag is truly a nag. If something <strong>must</strong> be done on a certain day, it will sit on the lock screen of my phone. I can snooze it for an hour if it’s not time sensitive, and if it really can wait, I can put off until next day.</p>

<p>Now I can say, “Hey, Siri, add build a robot to my inbox” and she will. Later, I can run the script which will migrate (including deleting) the reminder to an Inbox in TaskPaper, which I can move to an appropriate project or create a new one if it is warranted. My next goal is to set up a cron job on the always-on iMac to run the script every night.</p>

<p>For iOS, I’ve tried a few different apps for TaskPaper, but it seems <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/editorial/id673907758?at=10lKmy">Editorial</a> is going to stick. Also, I’ve not given up on Omnifocus for long term project tracking or potentially work related where contexts and due dates might be necessary, something OF excels at. An upcoming update to <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/omnifocus-2/id904071710?at=10lKmy">Omnifocus for iOS</a> will vastly expand on the URL schemes, and there is already a demo using <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/workflow-powerful-automation/id915249334?at=10lKmy">WorkFlow</a> to build projects in OF from TaskPaper formatted lists in Editorial. Sounds snazzy.</p>

<p>All in all my new system isn’t that fancy or original, but again, that’s the trap of chasing productivity, apps and systems. They become complicated and burdensome to the point you abandon them for the next shiny object, never truly doing the stuff you really wanted to keep track of in the first place.</p>

<p>I hope when I visit this in the fall, I’ve not made many changes and can focus on what I’ve accomplished over the summer.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Performance is a Feature</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/performance-is-a-feature/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-25T00:07:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-25T00:07:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/performance-is-a-feature</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I spent last evening making the necessary tweaks to this site to get a perfect 100% score on Google’s
<a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/">Pagespeed Insights</a>. I understand this is just a personal site, but at the root,understanding how to make this site fast will translate to helping bigger projects keep an eye out for potential bottle necks.</p>

<p>Which is why when Aaron Gustafson <a href="https://twitter.com/AaronGustafson/status/724448660076027904">tweeted</a> this posts headline, it caught my eye.</p>

<blockquote>
Either way, you could do much worse than to make your bit of the web fast.
<cite><a href="https://peterchamberlin.com/fast.php">Peter Chamberlin</a></cite></blockquote>

<p>The context was more broad and I believe directed towards larger sites, but it has to start somewhere.</p>

<p>Also, I plan on sharing how I implemented the changes to get to 100%, specifically the critical CSS.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Customizing Atom Editor</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/customizing-atom-editor/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-22T03:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-22T03:15:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/customizing-atom-editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I doubt anyone who writes code for a living or tinkers for that matter hasn’t spent more hours than they’d care to admit tweaking their editor of choice. Suffice to say, I’m in that boat all to well.</p>

<p>My current editor of choice is <a href="http://atom.io">Atom</a>. It’s open source and more than fits the customization itch.</p>

<p>Aside from deciding on which packages to use (I’ve
<a href="https://atom.io/users/miklb/stars">starred the ones I use</a>) the other element I’ve gone back and forth with is theme &amp; syntax UI. I’ve long been a fan of both Solarized Light and Dark, but have finally settled on Atom Dark and <a href="https://atom.io/themes/oceanic-next">Oceanic Next</a>. I can also recommend <a href="https://olivermak.es">Oliver Pattison’s</a> <a href="https://atom.io/users/opattison">Newbound syntax themes</a> My dream font is Operator Mono, but until I can justify the purchase of that, I’m using <a href="http://input.fontbureau.com/info/">Input</a>.</p>

<p>One tweak I just discovered is for adjusting the font size in the panel, or the sidebar. I’d been able to easily make the font larger for code/markdown, but sometimes had to break the readers out to discern what file was what in a nested folder. To the rescue I found <code class="highlighter-rouge">atom-panel.tool-panel</code> for just that. I’m currently using <code class="highlighter-rouge">1.4em</code>. Mind you this is on my old 11 inch Air. I’ve not had as much an issue on the iMac.</p>

<p>Another tweak I’ve added to my custom <code class="highlighter-rouge">styles.less</code> file is to italicize attributes. I’m also a fan of italicized comment blocks, which is included in the snippet.</p>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="na">atom-text-editor</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="n">shadow</span><span class="err">{</span>
     <span class="nc">.entity.other.attribute-name</span> <span class="err">{</span>
         <span class="nl">font-style</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nb">italic</span><span class="err">;</span>
     <span class="err">}</span>

     <span class="nc">.comment</span> <span class="err">{</span>
       <span class="nl">font-style</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nb">italic</span><span class="err">;</span>
     <span class="err">}</span>
 <span class="err">}</span>
</code></pre>
</div>
<p>I’m sure as I expand my development world, (I have a goal to learn python by <a href="https://miklb.com/building-a-twitterbot">Building a Twitterbot</a> ) I’ll continue to tweak Atom, but for now, I’m as close to happy with an editor as I have ever been. Feel free to share with me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/miklb">@miklb</a> your tips and trick.
<a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/title/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-19T17:19:28Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-19T17:19:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>/62368</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>World's most expensive scratching post</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Interest in Tampa Homebrew Website Club?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/interest-in-tampa-homebrew-website-club/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-19T14:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-19T14:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/interest-tampa-homebrew-website-club</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Gauging interest in Tampa to see if anyone would be up for joining a
<a href="https://indiewebcamp.com/events/2016-04-06-homebrew-website-club">Homebrew Website Club</a>. A lot of tech folks have vey neglected personal sites and this would give folks a chance to get together and talk tech and work on their personal site and pet proejcts. Platform agnostic (read, not another WordPress meetup) so open to anyone. If interested ping me on <a href="https://twitter.com/miklb">Twitter @miklb</a> for now and I’ll sort out finding a location and setting up a time. Only looking for a couple of people to get off the ground.</p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Headings - What Was Old is New Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/headings-what-was-old-is-new-again/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-18T13:10:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-18T13:10:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/headings-what-was-old-is-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Seems HTML WG has reversed course on a previous recommendation that allowed <code class="highlighter-rouge">sections</code> to have their own <code class="highlighter-rouge">H1</code> tag, now recommending the previous norm of cascading H tags.</p>

<blockquote>
Given that this bug has been around, and not fixed in browsers, for many  
years, we are proposing to remove the suggestion, and return to the model  
where elements `h1..h6` have a defined level of their own.
<cite><a href="https://lists.w3.org/Archives/Public/public-html/2016Apr/0032.html">HTML WG</a></cite>


<a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a>
</blockquote>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dogfooding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/dogfooding/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-17T17:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-17T17:27:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/dogfooding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>Last night I switched over the <em>theme</em> for this site to a project I’ve been working on the last moth or so, <a href="https://github.com/miklb/jekyll-indieweb">Jekyll-IndieWeb</a>. While I have different design ideas, until I find other users interested in using it, I knew I needed to work out any kinks. I also wanted to have better microformat support until the design changes. Thus
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eating_your_own_dog_food">dogfooding</a>.</p>

<p>I will write more about the project once I have more documentation (and work out any more said kinks), but the gist is I wanted to provide someone new to Jekyll with a desire to be part of the
<a href="https://indiewebcamp.com/">IndieWeb</a> a solid starting point. I rely heavily on the <code class="highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> file for options a user can set - profile pic, social media links, choice to include display of webmentions - to quickly get a personal site up and running. The biggest hurdle for me was providing a minimal design that was unopinionated yet still aesthetically appealing. Anyone familiar with HTML &amp; CSS can easily build upon or modify it, but if not, it shouldn’t look <em>ugly</em>.</p>

<p>This has been the first solo project I’ve embarked on that was meant for public consumption from the start, which in itself has been a learning process. Now I just hope others can find it useful in some way. If the project interests you I encourage you to try it out, open any issues in the repo, or reach out on #indiewebcamp IRC, I tend to hang around there most days.</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rough Take on Jekyll</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/rough-take-on-jekyll/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/rough-take-on-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>In a longer discussion about the recent pitch by Medium to content creators to move to their platform and options for new companies to build a site on, this nugget on whether Jekyll is an option:</p>

<blockquote>
Only usable by developers. About as accessible as improv Klingon slam poetry to anybody else.

- <cite><a href="https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/notes/choosing-a-host">Baldur Bjarnason</a> </cite>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Solving the Mysterious Relaunching iTunes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/solving-the-mysterious-relaunching-itunes/?utm_source=RSS&amp;utm_medium=RSS" />
    <published>2016-04-05T14:57:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-05T14:57:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>/solving-the-mysterious-relaunching-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>I had been plagued by an issue on my Macbook Air the last couple of months where iTunes would relaunch mysteriously. Not random relaunch mysteriously, more like, as soon as I quit, it would relaunch. I tried force quit and restarts. I trashed cache files and rebuilt the library to no avail. I filed bug reports and feedback to iTunes. Finally I reached out to @AppleSupport on Twitter. Right after (mind you, I DM’ed the account as they asked and so far no further reply) my internet friend <a href="https://twitter.com/shep">@shep</a> linked to a blog post of his from 4 years ago with his own <a href="https://iamshep.net/2012/08/the-never-ending-saga-of-itunes-launching-itself/">saga of iTunes relaunching</a>. I read through, and while I didn’t have headphones plugged in, I have dozed off a few times with my headphones in, and maybe, as he read about the microswitch in the jack, maybe, just maybe the headphones pulled out slightly &amp; not depressing said microswitch. So I forcefully inserted some headphones and quickly pulled the plug out of the jack. I quit iTunes and <em>so far</em>, iTunes hasn’t relaunched.</p>

<p>Did I mention @AppleSupport hasn’t followed up yet?</p>

<p><a href="https://brid.gy/publish/twitter"></a></p>
 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>
