<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miklb&#39;s Mindless Ramblings</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>miklb.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="miklb.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 09:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 09:33:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Focused Blogs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my ever revolving attempt to reboot my blog, one thing that has always slowed me down was my concern with being too esoteric in my topics. I want to talk about food, technology and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if I want to build any readership (isn’t that a part of blogging, sharing your thoughts with others?) I can’t be mixing in posts about forays into Python with posts about cooking vegetables sous-vide. Sure, there might be a readership that is interested in both topics as I am, but not enough to say “screw it.” So as I continue to work towards a true &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiewebcamp.com&quot;&gt;indieweb&lt;/a&gt;, I’m pivoting a bit in my approach and will use this as domain, now 11 years old, as my base identifier and central clearing house. I’ve acquired several domains, 2 of which will be good to split the topics. Those too will be static Jekyll built sites, with links from this site to new posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly this is more me thinking out loud and putting it out there, as I intend for this domain to be, but my goal is to continue to do such here, rather than bottle  up my thoughts in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/publish/twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/focused-blogs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/focused-blogs</guid>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Testing Sending Webmentions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is either going to go well, or well, not so well. But we are getting there. Slowly.  Last one for the night. Take 2. Day 2.&lt;a href=&quot;https://kartikprabhu.com/notes/test-note-totally-te&quot; class=&quot;u-in-reply-to&quot;&gt;Thanks for the help Kartik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/testing-sending-webmentions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/testing-sending-webmentions</guid>
        
        <category>test</category>
        
        <category>webmention</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making the Move to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve officially made the change from Habari to Jekyll. I will certainly have more to share on the move, both a post-mortem on Habari, as well as the process I’m using currently for using Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic workflow currently is serving the page from GitHub pages, however I’m using Travis CI to build the site and  publish to master branch&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; , there by bypassing the restrictions of gh-pages (specifically, their need for using –safe mode and not up-to-date version of Jekyll). Currently my use case would probably work within their parameters, however I had already started using 3.x and at the time of writing GitHub is using 2.x.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly to me, I want to be able to blog from my phone. It something that I feel has limited me in sharing interesting items I come across as well as stopping me from making time to put thoughts down as they come. I had originally wrote up &lt;a href=&quot;http://miklb.com/first-thoughts-holy-grail-of-blogging-from-ios-with-jekyll&quot;&gt;some thoughts on using iOS and Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, but later came across a better workflow&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are still some wonkiness around, I’m sure my Atom feed is broken and am not sure how to redirect that yet using GitHub. I doubt I had many subscribers, so if you stumble on this and previously read my random posts, you may need to update while I investigate options. Certainly there are some styling issues that I want to address as well as some under the hood improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://eshepelyuk.github.io/2014/10/28/automate-github-pages-travisci.html&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; was an invaluable starting point. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://mlota.github.io/2015/11/23/automating-deployment-github-pages-jekyll-travis.html&quot;&gt;follow up tutorial from the comments&lt;/a&gt; has great information as well. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Since I already own Drafts, Workflow and Working Copy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.matteocappadonna.org/Posting-with-Drafts,-Working-Copy-and-Workflow&quot;&gt;integrating all 3&lt;/a&gt; makes sense. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/making-the-move-to-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/making-the-move-to-jekyll</guid>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Habari</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Embracing My Suckiness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some know I used to cook for a living. I’d like to think I was pretty good at it too. I started before the Food Network and all the other cooking shows on TV (save for old Julia Childs and Jacques Pepin shows on PBS and the like), before the internet blew up. Cooking in Tampa was almost like being in a vacuum.  You’d see what your peers were doing, maybe find a little time to travel to Miami or New Orleans, but otherwise, we were left to our own curiosity, a few books from some of the chefs on the cutting edge (Mark Miller and the staff at Coyote Cafe, Norma Van Aiken and his contemporaries like Allen Susser &amp;amp; Mark Militello) and the occasional &lt;em&gt;Food &amp;amp; Wine&lt;/em&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explored other cuisines via ethnic dining, scoured Oceanic Market for Asian ingredients, the markets of West Tampa for authentic Latin/Caribbean staples, and the open air markets outside the commercial produce market. We were then left to our imagination, creativity, and abilities to marry flavors together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was kinda like how it was when I first started building websites. You’d look at someone’s source code. Someone might have written a blog post, or shared a tip in a forum somewhere. You bought Zeldman’s book on HTML standards, or Andy Budd’s CSS Mastery. It was a path of discovery and learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in this “age of information”, we (I), am bombarded with all of the latest tricks and best practices, cutting edge designs and techniques.  The external pressure to live up to these can be overwhelming. I’m no longer experimenting and discovering on my own, I’m drowning in information. It’s like having an elevator straight to the top of the mountain without experiencing the journey (I think that’s a paraphrase of something I read once about doing LSD, but I digress.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what I’m finding is that I’m a deer in the headlights, afraid that I’ll be judged for not using the latest markup techniques. That someone will see my code and think I suck. And rather than embrace my suckiness, learn from it, I freeze. I stare at blank pages in my text editor. Meanwhile, new and more information continues to bombard me from every angle, and the cycle perpetuates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, when I cook at home, I’m not worried about having all the fancy ingredients or flashy sous vide machine. I’m confident in my skills and &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; the finished dish will look appetizing and taste better. Or, I might &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; miss the mark, but will recognize what I did wrong or forgot, storing it away in my memory bank or nowadays, jotted into a text file for the next time I make a similar dish. That’s not to say when time permits I don’t use those fancy ingredients or make my pasta from scratch but a good meal shouldn’t be passed up simply because I didn’t have artisanal cheese and didn’t make my pasta from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I struggle to reboot my personal site and convert it to Jekyll, I need to recognize that I don’t have to follow every new trend. So what if it wasn’t built in Sass. The work I put into making it responsive, and FAST is more important in the long run. There are plenty of sites/devs out there that have well structured Sass directories and all the right mixins, but load slow as hell. There is plenty of time in the future to revisit converting it. The end goal for this site isn’t about being a Sass master, but an outlet to share my thoughts and experiences on the web. Why create an artificial hurdle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which also means I need to document my failures, as well as successes. Whether that means publicly, or internally. Not only document them, but celebrate them. I need to reconnect with that ambitious kid who would spend every waking hour in the kitchen experimenting, enjoying the journey. Thus starts my journey of documenting this phase of my site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/embracing-my-suckiness</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/embracing-my-suckiness</guid>
        
        <category>cooking</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>Sass</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Web Ad Dilemma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about this subject quite a bit lately. While tools like Safari’s &lt;em&gt;Reader View&lt;/em&gt; can help, the desire to support advertising on the web is impossible to square with the current implementation on most web sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jimray&quot;&gt;Jim Ray&lt;/a&gt; breaks it down much more succinctly than I have been able to. &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickerfusion.com/blocking-ad-blockers-with-better-ads.html&quot;&gt;Blocking ad-blockers with better ads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The problem may be murky, but the solution is a bit more clear, if not exactly novel: build a better product. Not a fancier iPad app, a better ad product. For all the haranguing about native ads, they have the advantage of being immune to filters and, when done right, a genuinely better experience, certainly better than green double-underlines or the “content marketing platform” ads at the bottom of far too many web pages.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just give me a well designed, compelling advertisement. Hell, I’ll share my browsing history if that is what it takes to serve me something I’m genuinely interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/the-web-ad-dilemma</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/the-web-ad-dilemma</guid>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>advertising</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tunesday: Bully</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This band just rocks me. I can not wait for the whole record. God knows what bands they listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Albini, do your homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixies? Sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nirvana? Had to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bands I missed out when I was doing stuff? I want to know them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, more music like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kq3rNIYUwU0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That bass line. Be still the 23 year old still in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/tunesday-bully</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/tunesday-bully</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>Tunesday</category>
        
        <category>Bully</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Thoughts: Holy Grail of Blogging from iOS with Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been researching and thinking seriously about moving away from database driven blog engines to &lt;em&gt;static file&lt;/em&gt; blogging for quite awhile. My extensive research has me convinced for my ideal workflow, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; will be the answer—except for my goal to somewhat easily blog from my phone. All of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt; could be handled by TextExpander snippets or custom keyboard shortcuts in Drafts or Editorial. The issue has been that with an iOS device, you are basically confined to using Dropbox or iCloud for the text/markdown files. Wanting to keep everything in a Git repo under version control, I hadn’t found a way to automagically push a Dropbox file to a Git repo without having an always on machine at home using some listening app like &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt; to do this. While that isn’t out of the question, I want something &lt;strong&gt;straight from the device&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extensive Googling finally led me to Zappier. Similar to IFTTT, they have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/zapbook/dropbox/github/&quot;&gt;Github/Dropbox workflow&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to send a pull request to Github when a new file is added to a directory in Dropbox. And while if I was simply using Github pages to host a Jekyll site, that would be the end to a simple solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I still want to host my own data on my own VPS (more on that later). Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/developmentseed/jekyll-hook&quot;&gt;Jekyll Hook&lt;/a&gt;, which, while not seemingly for the faint of heart, allows one to run their own “Github Pages” on their own server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while all untested at this point, on paper it seems I can have a dedicated Dropbox folder synced with an iOS editor that when a markdown file is saved to it, Zapier will attempt to send a pull request and merge it to a Github hosted repo of my blog [footnote, possibly need to have iOS app to approve pull request but option is in the &lt;em&gt;recipe&lt;/em&gt; for the workflow. I assume it will work save for any previous files by same name causing a merge conflict]. From that, the Jekyll Hook script/solution will fire and rebuild the the site, all without leaving the convenience of my iOS device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential magic I tell you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/first-thoughts-holy-grail-of-blogging-from-ios-with-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/first-thoughts-holy-grail-of-blogging-from-ios-with-jekyll</guid>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Github</category>
        
        <category>Dropbox</category>
        
        <category>Zappier</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Email is so 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;tl;dr Wouldn&#39;t it be nice if in the newfound popularity of email newsletters, the signup form had an option &quot;I regularly consume your content via another means, but would love to win your cool thing&quot;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the dark days of the internet, websites would have simple sign up forms for users to get updates about the site. Unless you used RSS (or Atom) to read the sites. Even then, online marketers and brands would offer specials not advertised on their site to build the engagement via email. The size of your mailing list was a badge of honor for those marketers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came along social media, and email lists were pushed aside for the shiny new thing. In the beginning, there was a glut of social media options, and it was almost impossible for a brand to engage on &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; outlet. Facebook likes and Twitter followers became the new badge of honor. And while social media is still a great way to engage users, brands and marketers soon discovered they couldn’t always control the message, especially with Facebook. So what did they do? They realized the most common form of communication available to the web is the venerable method of email. &lt;em&gt;Cyber Monday&lt;/em&gt; was a perfect example. I couldn’t count the number of comments I read on Twitter about people weeding their email of offers from long ago forgotten sites. But I mostly follow web professionals who know the ins-and-outs of online marketing and get their information from, (well, probably Twitter, but they are an anomalous subset of the Twittersphere.) The point being, millions of people woke to an inbox of offers. Many people clicked those links, some bought stuff. It works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;left&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.miklb.com/images/wirecutter_form.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sign up form for The Wirecutter&quot; /&gt;RSS/Atom syndication in its purest form is not a common method of reading websites today (unless you are part of the aforementioned anomalous subset of Twitter users), but still provides the backbone of many ways content is consumed. But this isn’t about syndication. It is about the rebirth of mailing lists, and more specifically, the forms that sites now deploy to get you in. Those lists sign-ups are generally there year round, but right about the holiday season, sites/brands begin offering “free stuff.” Be it a book, a song or a full suite of electronics, sign up for their mailing list, enter a chance to win. I’m not an expert on this subject, didn’t even play an email marketer on TV. &lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://cdn.miklb.com/images/seriouseats_form.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sign up form for The Wirecutter&quot; /&gt;But my understanding is you can’t force people into subscribing, just like contests have the small disclaimer, “no purchase necessary.” Generally what these forms do is pre-populate the subscribe checkbox, which is still a slippery slope in my opinion of conforming to the spirit of opting in. But hey, a free TV is a free TV?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to the point, there is never an option (at least one I’ve encountered) that says, “I love your content and regularly read it so I don’t need an email reminder. However, I’d love to win your cool stuff.” Hell, provide a short text box to allow the user to optionally add &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; they consume it. It very well might be a great insight into your audience and their online consumption habits. Because at some point, inundating your readers/consumers will call into play the law of diminishing returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I’m afraid the new badge of honor is the hydra of social media followers guarding the treasure chest of email subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/email-is-so-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/email-is-so-2015</guid>
        
        <category>email</category>
        
        <category>marketing</category>
        
        <category>twitter</category>
        
        <category>facebook</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Engaging Users Vs. Advertising</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen the headline bandied about in social media all week, but over on &lt;cite&gt;Unapologetic&lt;/cite&gt; Alex Guyot discusses his disagreement with &lt;a href=&quot;http://unapologetic.io/posts/2014/11/14/facebook-makes-it-harder-again-for-brands-to-advertise-for-free/&quot;&gt;Facebook making it harder (again) for brands to advertise for free.&lt;/a&gt;. His basic argument is that brands most likely already bought the likes and shouldn’t have to pay to advertise again to those same customers. He also uses the argument that small businesses likely can’t afford to advertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t disagree more with his take. From the Re/code article of the same name &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the author quotes the Facebook release&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The company announced today it will begin limiting the number of “promotional Page posts” in the News Feed starting in January. That means you’ll see fewer posts from brands asking you to buy products or “enter promotions and sweepstakes,” Facebook wrote in a blog post.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see no issue with that statement. While we all know we are the product on Facebook &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I still use it to keep up with family and friends, as well as local goings on. I have “liked” very few &lt;em&gt;brands&lt;/em&gt;, mostly local businesses. Truthfully, those local businesses don’t use what I would consider “promotions or sweepstakes” or obvious ad-like updates. They are genuinely engaging their followers. Sharing pics of a new dish. Updating on what band or artist is appearing soon. They respond to questions and comments. As you should in social media. So if cutting down on the noise from million plus “fan” businesses in timelines so that the news feed is a truly a “news” feed with targeted ads, and people don’t miss the latest update from the mom &amp;amp; pop shop down the street, I’m all for it. It is well documented that brands and businesses that truly engage their users/followers are the most successful. Perhaps this will push those brands to up their game. Otherwise, it can be a great equalizer for brands and companies looking to gain market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://recode.net/2014/11/14/facebook-news-feed-update-cuts-down-on-promotional-brand-posts/&quot;&gt;Facebook Makes it harder (again) to for brands to advertise for free.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://readwrite.com/2014/11/13/facebook-privacy-policy-transactions-data-location-targeted-advertising&quot;&gt;Facebook’s Latest “You Are The Product” Message: We Will, We Will, Sell You&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/engaging-users-vs-advertising</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/engaging-users-vs-advertising</guid>
        
        <category>advertising</category>
        
        <category>facebook</category>
        
        <category>social-media</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technology Fatigue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A piece at &lt;cite&gt;A List Apart&lt;/cite&gt; today struck a nerve with a lot of developers today, myself included (if I can really call myself a developer these days.) &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/blog/post/overwhelmed-by-code&quot;&gt;Overwhelmed by Code&lt;/a&gt; touches on the constant bombardment to developers from new technologies popping up seemingly daily. The author discusses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;It used to be that knowing CSS and HTML was enough, then jQuery came along, then responsive techniques, then Node.js and then Angular, Ember, etc., etc., etc. That list, right there, it tires me out.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that I can completely relate. When I stumbled into making websites, they were still teaching how to use Photoshop and tables to build sites at my local community college, not pure CSS. The big revelation at &lt;cite&gt;A List Apart&lt;/cite&gt; was &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/fauxcolumns&quot;&gt;Faux Columns&lt;/a&gt;. So fast forward 10 years, take a sabbatical for 2 of those, and you can imagine how overwhelming stepping back into grunt, gulp, coffee script, node and Luce&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;What do I want to focus on, what do I love about the web? What do I actually want to learn, versus what I think I should learn. &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if I am to do more than dip my toes back into the world of building websites, I too need to focus on what I I think will best benefit me professionally, not try and keep up with kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Actually, Luce is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://open.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/10/30/programming-language-or-shakespeare-character/?_r=0&quot;&gt;Shakespeare character, not a programming language&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>miklb.com/technology-fatigue</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">miklb.com/technology-fatigue</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
